A Guide to the Sargent and Company Records 1980.0038
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series III: Correspondence, undated, 1884-1942
  - Subseries A: General Correspondence, 1884-1912
    - Bar - Bro, 1898-1902; (15 folders) (Box 22)
    - Bry - Cy, 1898-1902; (15 folders) (Box 23)
    - Cro - Har, 1898-1902; (14 folders) (Box 24)
    - Har - Lan, 1898-1902; (15 folders) (Box 25)
    - Lan - Ov, 1898-1902; (16 folders) (Box 26)
    - Pa - Rog, 1894-1901; (15 folders) (Box 27)
    - Rog - Sti, 1894-1901; (14 folders) (Box 28)
    - Sto - Zu, 1898-1901; (16 folders) (Box 29)
    - A - C, T - W, 1884-1912; (5 folders) (Box 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1911-1915; (26 folders)
    - General Correspondence, 1915-1918; (40 folders) (Box 31)
  - Subseries B: Selected Topical Correspondence, 1896-1942
    - Association of Manufacturers, 1848-1903; (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Cast iron A - Z, 1890-1901
    - Casket hardware, 1876-1894, 1900-1906; (2 folders)
    - Coffin hardware, 1900-1902; (12 folders)
    - Coons, H.T. Chicago Agency, 1902; (3 folders)
    - Foundry data, 1899
    - French, Howard, 1899-1900
    - French, Howard, 1889-1902; (9 folders) (Box 33)
    - Hardware, general, 1892-1900
    - Hopkins Grammar School, 1923-1935
    - Inventors, 1915-197; (6 folders)
    - Liberty Loans, 1917-1918
    - Licenses, 1909, 1913
    - Machinery (5 folders), 1894-1917
    - Machinery (4 folders), 1911-1916 (Box 34)
    - O.P.A. (8 folders), 1942-1946
    - Purchase of plants and products, 1890-1905
    - Sargent, J.B.—Trips, 1887-1924; (6 folders)
    - Screws, 1893-1895
    - Traps and ringers, 1886
  - Subseries C: Sales Correspondence, 1886-1942
    - Brittingham, E. F., 1942
    - Crawford, A. J., 1942; (7 folders)
    - Cook, A. H., 1942
    - Edwards, B. P., 1942
    - Hammer, F. R., 1941-1942; (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Higgins, H. L., 1942
    - Hoogkirk, S. O., 1942
    - Keyes, J. J., 1942
    - Lawrence, S. D., 1942
    - New York Agents, 1886; (7 folders)
    - New York, 1942; (2 folders)
    - Rafter squares, 1912-1915
    - Reid, A. L., 1942
    - Salaman, R. G., 1942
    - Frank Sample, Inc., 1942
    - Scott, W. D., 1942
    - Search, W. A., 1942
    - Sears and Roebuck, 1942; (3 folders)
    - Shapleigh Hardware, 1942
    - Strattman, H. S., 1942
    - Sullivan, W. C., 1942
    - Thalleen, N. J., 1942
    - Valentine, L. E., 1942
    - Van Housen, H. L., 1942
    - George Worthington Company, 1937-1942; (3 folders)
    - Wurzbach, A. J., 1942
    - Zeigler, A. C., 1942
  - Subseries D: Letter Copy Books, undated, 1887-1903
    - H. B. Sargent, 1887-1903; (3 v.) (Box 36)
    - E. R. Sargent, 1897-1898; (3 v.)
    - E. R. Sargent, 1899; (2 v.) (Box 37)
    - New York letter books, 1897-1900; (4 v.)
    - New York letter books, 1898-1901; (5 v.) (Box 38)
    - Credits to Sargent Company, 1895-1898; (1 v.)
    - Credits to Sargent Company, 1899-1901; (1 v.) (Box 39)
    - Order books, 1894-1898; (4 v.)
    - Order books, 1898-1900; (4 v.) (Box 40)
    - General letter book, 1897-1898; (1 v.)
    - General letter book, 1898-1900; (5 v.) (Box 41)
    - General letter book, 1900-1905; (5 v.) (Box 42)
    - Unidentified letter book, undated; (4 v.) (Box 43)
- Series IV: Production Records, undated, 1866-1950
  - Subseries A: Machinery Repair Manuals, undated, 1913-1914
    - Book No. 1 (machines 1-1908), undated (Box 44)
    - Book No. 2 (machines 1909-3826), undated (Box 45)
    - Book No. 3 (machines 3827-5663), undated (Box 46)
    - Care, Maintenance and Repair, 1913-1914 (Box 47)
  - Subseries B: Plant Orders, undated, 1823-1850
    - 65728-72945, 1923 January - October (Box 47)
    - 72946-80022, 1924 October - July
    - 80040-87942, 1924 July - 1925 June
    - 87943-95127, 1925 June - 1926 March (Box 48)
    - 1-7734, 1927
    - 97994-101673 (record sheets), 1926-1927
    - 200-7195, undated
  - Subseries C: Inventories, 1880-1900, 1948-1950
    - Record of inventory, 1888-1900 (Box 49)
    - Inventory, 1889-1894 (Box 50)
    - Inventories (raw materials, work in progress, finished goods), 1948-1950 (Box 51)
  - Subseries D: Production, 1866-1950
    - Cost of wrought iron, 1866-1870 (Box 52)
    - Metal mixtures, 1889-1894; (2 folders)
    - Calorimeters, 1903
    - Gas used by department, 1921-1925
    - Inventories and shipments, 1923-1927; (3 folders)
    - Scrap charge summary, 1924-1930
    - Standard material prices, 1918-1926
    - French visit to view production, 1950
  - Subseries E: Specifications--World War II Production, 1940-1949
    - Alden and Eldredge McInnis, Inc., 1942
    - Army and Navy, 1942-1944; (5 folders)
    - Army and Navy, 1942-1944; (3 folders) (Box 53)
    - Army purchase information, 1943
    - Army-Navy builders hardware, c. 1940-1949
    - Selling to the Navy, 1940
    - Bidder's reference book, 1942
    - Consolidating Shipbuilding Corporation, 1942
    - Lock conversion, 1942
    - Packaging and packing, 1942-1944
    - Emergency Product Committee meetings, 1942
    - Emergency Product Changes, 1942; (3 folders)
    - Emergency specifications for builders hardware, 1940-1942
    - Catonments, 1940-1942; (5 folders)
    - Defense Housing Critical list, 1942
    - Permanent Public buildings, 1942
  - Subseries F: Blueprints, 1920-1944
    - Defense Department, 1922-1924; (approx. 25) (Box 54)
    - Ordnance, 1943; (2 v.) (Box 55)
    - Army Air Corps drawings, 1942 (Box 56)
    - Army ordnance drawings, 1941-1943
    - Aviation ordnance—bomb shackles, 1943; (2 v.)
    - Chemical warfare, 1941
    - Engineer Corps drawings, 1920-1921, 1942
    - Medical Corps drawings, 1942
    - Navy ordnance drawings, 1942
    - Navy drawings, 1942
    - Signal Corps drawings, 1930-1943
    - War products drawings, 1942
    - Ordnance assembly blueprints, 1941-1942 (Box 57)
    - Special and ordnance blueprints, 1941-1943
    - Quartermaster Corps, 1921-1940; (3 v.)
  - Subseries G: Process Sheets and Production Schedules, undated, 1944, 1946
    - Bomb rack MK 47 sheets (Box 58)
      - 1 - 100, undated
      - 101 - 200, undated
      - 201 - 279, undated
    - Production schedule
      - 1944, (1 v.)
      - A - G, 1946
      - H - L, 1946
      - M - Z, 1946
  - Subseries H: Product Cost Records [See note above for sampling technique], 1916-1924
    - Adjusters to Butts (Box 59)
    - Butts (Box 60)
    - Bolts (Box 61-62)
    - Coffin Hardware (Box 63-64)
    - Transom lifts to door checks (Box 65)
    - Door checks (Box 66)
    - Escutcheons (Box 67-68)
    - Locks (Box 69-70)
    - Eyes to sash fasteners (Box 71)
    - Sash cord irons to door knobs (Box 72)
    - Case fasteners (Box 73)
    - Plane to label plate (Box 74)
    - Old cost sheets (Box 75-81)
    - Obsolete (Box 82-83)
- Series V: Labor Records, 1864-1927
  - Subseries A: Employee Registers, 1854-1919
    - Employee Register Index, 1864-1902 (Box 84-85)
    - Employee Register, 1864-1919 (Box 86-91)
  - Subseries B: Wage Ledgers, 1873-1907
    - Monday, 1873-1875 (Box 92)
    - Saturday, 1875-1879 (Box 93)
    - Tuesday, 1880-1882 (Box 94)
    - Tuesday, 1886-1887 (Box 95)
    - Wages ledgers, 1874-1907 (Box 96-117)
    - Department 1, 1890-1897 (Box 118-120)
    - Department 2, 1894-1897 (Box 121-122)
    - Department 3, 1893-1894 (Box 123)
    - Department 6, 1892-1897 (Box 124)
    - Department 7, 1893-1897 (Box 125-126)
    - Department 8, 1894-1897 (Box 127-129)
    - Department 9, 1893-1897 (Box 130-131)
    - Department 10, 1892-1897 (Box 132-133)
    - Department 12, 1894-1897 (Box 134)
    - Department 14, 1893-1897 (Box 135)
    - Department 15, 1892-1897 (Box 136)
    - Department 17, 1891-1897 (Box 137-138)
    - Department 18, 1891-1897 (Box 139-141)
    - Department 19, 1891-1897 (Box 142-143)
    - Department 24, 1889-1896 (Box 144)
    - Department 25, 1889-1895 (Box 145)
    - Department 26, 1893-1897 (Box 146-147)
    - Department 28, 1894-1897 (Box 148)
    - Department 31, 1894-1897 (Box 149-150)
    - Department 35, 1892-1897 (Box 151)
    - Wages, 1899 (Box 152-153)
  - Subseries C: Salary Ledgers, 1911-1927
    - Salary ledgers, 1911-1927 (Box 154-155)
  - Subseries D: Piece Work Ledgers, 1886, 1891-1897
    - Wages, 1886 (Box 156)
    - Wages, 1891-1897 (Box 157-162)
  - Subseries E: Contracts, 1895-1919
    - Labor contract book, 1915-1919 (Box 163)
    - Contractor's earnings, 1895-1898 (Box 164)
    - Contractor's earnings, 1907 (Box 164a)
  - Subseries F: Other Labor records, 1867-1951
    - Accident reports, 1893-1915, 1923-1929 (Box 165)
    - Casket Hardware Association, 1904-1905
    - Committee of Manufacturers Association of Connecticut Re: Workmen's compensation, 1911-1913
    - Compensation, 1910-1915; (5 folders)
    - Department key, 1924
    - Dinners and social events, 1893-1927
    - Employee benefits, 1913, 1917, 1931
    - National Metal Trades Association, New Haven Branch, 1909
    - Newspaper clippings, 1912, 1914-1915, 1945
    - Office and factory rules, 1867, 1926, 1942
    - Payroll, 1935-1944; (4 folders)
    - Payroll distribution, 1943-1944
    - Payroll, weekly distribution (Ziegler Sargent), 1933-1937
    - Wage Distribution Policy, 1951
    - Wages, rates, 1891-1895
    - Wages, review, 1882
    - Working conditions, 1926, 1931, 1938-1946; (8 folders)
    - Sargent General Rules (poster), 1930 (Box OS)
    - Suspense Ledger, 1894-1912 (Volume 342)
- Series VI: Sales, 1852-1955
  - Subseries A: Sales Records, 1870-1948
    - Notices to Salesmen
      - Prices, 1919 (Box 166)
      - Prices, 1920-1922
      - Prices, 1932; (3 folders)
      - Prices, 1933; (3 folders)
    - Sales Convention programs, 1915-1929; (2 folders)
    - Sales Convention: Talks by Engineers, 1948
    - Sales Manual, 1925
    - Publications
      - "Builders' Hardware from the Ground Up", 1924
      - "Hardware for Utility and Ornamentation", 1927
    - Confidential prices, 1917-1922; (20 folders)
    - Net competitive prices, 1937-1945
    - Prices and estimates, 1870-1895; (6 folders) (Box 167)
    - Price change sheets, 1921; (3 folders)
    - Price lists, 1914
    - Lock prices, 1924
    - Price change book, 1877-1879
    - Price change book, 1892-1895
    - Sales account book: exports, 1881-1905
    - Product lists, 1888
    - Sales account book, 1893-1910
    - Sales account book, 1898
    - Special case book, 1911
    - Electrotype sales account book, 1914
    - Ordered on Factory, 1923-1926; (3 folders)
    - Sales projections, 1944
    - War line prices, 1944
    - Sales record book, 1871-1902 (Box 168)
    - Gas meter graphs, 1925-1927
    - Sales account book, 1925-1927 (Box 169)
    - Sales chart book, 1924-1926
  - Subseries B: Sales Journals, 1881-1901
    - Coffin hardware, 1890-1892 (Box 170)
    - Coffin hardware, 1896-1898 (Box 171)
    - Coffin hardware, 1899-1901 (Box 172)
    - Locks, 1891-1892 (Box 173)
    - Locks, 1894 (Box 174)
    - Locks, 1896 (Box 175)
    - New England Territory, 1881 (Box 176)
    - Locks, 1897 (Box 177)
    - Locks, 1897-1898 (Box 178)
    - Locks, 1898 (Box 179)
    - Locks, 1899 (Box 180)
    - Locks, 1899-1900 (Box 181)
    - Locks, 1900-1901 (Box 182)
    - Small locks, 1892 (Box 183)
    - Small locks, 1892-1893 (Box 184)
    - Small locks, 1893-1894 (Box 185)
    - Small exports, 1890-1892 (Box 186)
    - Small exports, 1896-1898 (Box 187)
    - Small exports, 1899-1901 (Box 188)
    - Small special 108, 1892-1895 (Box 189)
    - Small special 108, 1895-1898 (Box 190)
    - Small special 108, 1898-1899 (Box 191)
    - Small special, 1893-1894 (Box 192)
    - Small special, 1894-1895 (Box 193)
    - Small special, 1897-1898 (Box 194)
  - Subseries C: Catalogs, undated, 1852-1955
    - Sargent and Company
      - 1861, (6 v.) (Box 195)
      - 1863, (3 v.)
      - 1864, (2 v.)
      - undated, (2 v.)
      - Coffin hardware, 1866
      - 1866, (4 v.)
      - 1869, (5 v.)
      - 1870, (2 v.) (Box 196)
      - 1871, (8 v.)
      - 1874, (6 v.) (Box 197)
      - 1874, (3 v.) (Box 198)
      - 1877, (3 v.)
      - 1877-1879, (6 v.) (Box 199)
      - 1880, (3 v.) (Box 200)
      - 1880-1881, (1 v.)
      - 1880, (5 v.) (Box 201)
      - undated, (1 v.)
      - 1884, (5 v.) (Box 202)
      - 1884, (4 v.) (Box 203)
      - 1887, (2 v.) (Box 204)
      - Door locks, 1886
      - Door locks, 1887; (5 v.)
      - 1888, (2 v.)
      - B. design, 1889; (1 v.) (Box 205)
      - 1888, (4 v.)
      - 1894, (1 v.) (Box 206)
      - Screen hardware, 1913-1914 (Box 206)
      - Discount sheet, 1916
      - R. E. Voorhees copy, undated
      - Locks and Hardware, 1926; (2 v.)
      - Condensed price listing, 1936
      - Articles in stock, 1936
      - Marine hardware, 1936
      - Marine hardware, 1939
      - Marine hardware, 1943
      - Locks and hardware, limited war line, 1943; (2 v.)
      - Temporary catalogue #46, undated (Box 207)
      - Restricted Production line, undated
      - Limited war line, 1943
      - Catalogue #42, 1941
      - Marine hardware discount sheet, 1944
      - Locks and hardware, 1948; (3 v.)
      - Quick exit devices, 1955
    - Russell & Erwin, 1852
    - Russell & Erwin, 1856
    - Russell & Erwin, 1857
    - Davenport, Mallory & Company, 1867
    - Hogan, Clarke & Sleeper, 1874
    - Lumber yards of John F. Carr, 1886
    - Duggan Parker, 1884
    - O.S. Walker & Company, magnetic chucks, undated
    - Beardslee Chandelier Manufacturing Company, undated
    - Parker Metal-Goods Company, 1937
    - Richard-Wilcox Manufacturing, 1948
    - Stearns Lawnmower, catalogue #34, 1937
    - Harvey Rolling Hardware, 1947
    - Parker Wire Goods, 1947
    - Stover Hardware, catalogue #25, 1925
    - Earle Hardware Manufacturing Company, tubular lock and latch sets, 1949
    - American Watchman's Time Detector Company, undated
    - New York Lock Company, 1904
    - Ladd's Discount book, 1910
    - Merrill Manufacturing Company, catalogue #400, 1952
    - Larson Company, Condensed Price catalogue, 1949
    - Colonial Bronze Company, builders' hardware, 1940
    - M.S. Brooks, catalogue #103, 1949 (Box 207A)
    - Grand Specialties Company, 1947
    - Cincinnati Tool Company, catalogue #37, 1937
    - Bronson Company, catalogue #103, 1949
    - Hartford Clamp Company, catalog #60, undated
    - Armstrong Tools, catalogue S-48, 1948
    - Griswald Manufacturing Company, undated
    - A.W. Crossman and Son, price list, 1870
    - Hancock Tool Manufacturing Company, undated
    - Lund Equipment Co., Catalogue and price list #16, 1947
    - Vincent J. Lawler Company, 1949
    - Hindley Manufacturing Company, undated
    - Victor Manufacturing Company, undated
    - Architectural and Art Industrial Works, 1892
    - Sales Flyers, undated
    - Envelope for "Sargent Superior Bull Rings,", undated
    - Undated catalogues (Box 208)
    - Advertising scrapbooks, 1890-1909 (Box 209)
    - Advertising scrapbooks, 1911-1914 (Box 210)
    - Advertising scrapbooks, 1923-1926 (Box 211)
    - Advertising scrapbooks, 1927-1931 (Box 212)
    - Sample book, hardware, 1889-1892 (Box 213)
    - Sample book, coffin hardware, 1893 (Box 214)
    - Mallory, Wheeler & Co., catalogue, 1871 (Box 215)
    - Mallory, Wheeler & Co., catalogue, 1876 (Box 216)
- Series VII: General Accounts, 1858-1955
  - Subseries A: Cash Books, 1867-1910
    - 1867-1877 (Volume 222, Volume 221, Volume 220, Volume 219, Volume 218, Volume 217)
    - 1880-1884 (Volume 224, Volume 223, Volume 225)
    - 1888-1895 (Volume 229, Volume 230, Volume 227, Volume 228, Volume 226)
    - 1910 (Volume 231)
  - Subseries B: Day Books—New York Office, 1900-1910
    - 1900-1910 (Box 232-234)
  - Subseries C: Day Books, 1872-1880
    - 1872-1880 (Box 235)
  - Subseries D: Journals, 1864-1888, 1900-1927
    - 1864-1868 (Box 236-238)
    - 1900-1927 (Box 234-242)
    - 1858-1862 (Box 243)
    - 1868-1872 (Box 244-245)
  - Subseries E: Invoices Payable, 1899-1904
    - 1899-1904 (Box 246)
  - Subseries F: Check Registers, 1878, 1897, 1906-1910
    - 1878-1891 (Box 247)
    - 1893-1897, 1906-1910 (Box 248)
  - Subseries G: Trial Balances, 1897-1926
    - 1897-1926 (Box 249)
  - Subseries H: Ledgers, 1864-1928
    - New York series indexes, undated (Box 250-253)
    - New York series, 1871-1912 (Box 254-268)
    - New Haven series, 1883-1912 (Box 269-281)
    - Coffin Hardware series, 1885-1928 (Box 282-288)
    - State series A, 1911-1918 (Box 289-296)
    - State series B, 1918-1922 (Box 297-308)
    - State series C, 1922-1924 (Box 309-319)
    - Hand cards, 1874-1879 (Box 320)
    - Ledger A, 1864-1884 (Box 321-322)
    - Ledger, 1866-1871 (Box 323)
    - Ledger C, 1871-1873 (Box 324)
    - Ledger (New York), 1867-1874 (Box 325)
    - Ledger: receivables, 1889-1904 (Box 326-327)
    - Sargent Trust, 1884-1888 (Box 328)
    - Ledger, 1903-1927 (Box 329)
    - Suspense, 1924-1926 (Box 330)
    - Ledger sheets, undated (Box 331)
  - Subseries I: Financial Records and Accounts, 1868-1954
    - Ledgers: New Haven, 1889, 1910, 1918, 1922, 1926 (Box 332)
    - Ledger and journal: Chicago, 1911; (2 v.) (Box 333)
    - Ledger, 1900-1909 (Box 333)
    - Private ledger and journal: New York, 1922-1926; (2 v.)
    - Operating journal, 1927 (Box 334)
    - Payable, 1907-1918
    - Index, 1901-1909
    - Distribution, 1901-1910
    - Accounts, 1912-1929; (2 v.)
    - Internal financial statements, 1929-1946 (Box 335)
    - Insurance, 1868-1923
    - Account book, undated
    - Ledgers: Harris Bros., 1858-1869; (3 v.) (Box 336)
    - Inventory sheets, New Haven factories, 1873
    - Wright and Campbell, 1883-1884
    - Payroll log, 1885
    - Receipts: J. Bradford and H. Sargent, 1888-1902
    - Leger: City book, 1897-1899
    - Stock certificates: Sargent, 1887-1908
    - Balance sheet: Profit and Loss
      - Chicago, 1916-1918
      - New Haven, 1923-1926
      - New York, 1921, 1923, 1924; (3 v.)
      - General, 1926-1927
    - Trial balance, 1927
    - Financial forecasts, 1954
    - Statement of gross and operating profits, 1926 (Box 337)
    - Investments, 1926-1932; (3 folders)
- Series VIII: Predecessor and Subsidiary Companies, 1853-1879
  - Peck & Walter Manufacturing Company
    - Correspondence, 1921-1951 (Box 338)
    - Official Records, 1853-1858
    - Stock ledger, 1853-1856
    - 1855-1859, 3 volumes
    - Building drawing, 1853
  - Sargent Card Clothing Company
    - Record book, 1866-1879 (Box 338)
  - Sargent Wharf Company
    - Records, 1871
- Series IX: Sargent Family Papers, undated, 1720-1955
  - Denny Family Letters, c. 1720 (Box 339)
  - Colonel Paul Dudley Sargent, 1745-1827
  - Joseph D. Sargent
    - Correspondence, 1802-1846
    - Receipts and Contracts, 1807-1860
    - Estate papers, 1848-1856
    - Congregational Society report (reprint of 1820), 1953
  - Joseph Bradford Sargent
    - Biographical material, 1822-1907
    - Correspondence, 1840-1906
    - Wills and trusts, 1873-1893
    - Withdrawal of suit, Talcott H. Russell, 1875-1886
    - Promissory notes, 1870-1900
    - Addresses and articles, 1882-1905
    - Expressions of sympathy upon death, 1907
    - Memorabilia, undated
  - George Henry Sargent
    - Correspondence, biographical material, 1828-1917
    - Scrapbook, 1885-1917
  - Henry Bradford Sargent
    - Biographical materials, 1851-1927
    - Correspondence, addresses, 1864-1927
    - Genealogical correspondence, notes, 1897-1925
    - Clubs, 1890-1920
    - Colby Club, 1900-1927; (2 folders)
    - Harris County "Mill Tract" land: Legal records, 1892, 1897-1898
  - Henry Edward Sargent
    - Promissory notes, 1886-1900
  - Joseph Denny Sargent
    - Biographical material, 1860-1936
  - Zeigler Sargent
    - Correspondence, 1900-1955; (6 folders) (Box 340)
    - Manuscripts, undated; (9 folders)
    - Manuscripts, undated; (2 folders) (Box 341)
    - Notes, undated; (3 folders)
  - Patrizate Club, 1915-1949
  - Sargentrivia, v. I-XIII, 1943-1955; (13 folders)
  - Photographs: family and company buildings, c. 1890-1951; (5 folders)
  - Sargent Community Association, 1953
  - HSargent Yale button, 1841
  - Manufacturing and Mercantile interests, undated; (4 charts) (Box OS)
  - Photographs, New Haven Sales Organization, 1925 (Box OS)